<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<metadata>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>q40k</attrlabl>
				<attalias>40kHz</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if at least one file, that could not be assigned otherwise to species or group, could be assigned a 40kHz frequency group.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>my40</attrlabl>
				<attalias>40 kHz Myotis</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if at least one file, that could not be assigned otherwise to species, could be assigned as belonging to the 40kHz Myotis group.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>q50k</attrlabl>
				<attalias>50kHz</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if at least one file, that could not be assigned otherwise to species or group, could be assigned a  50kHz frequency group.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>anpa</attrlabl>
				<attalias>ANPA</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Antrozous pallidus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>cora</attrlabl>
				<attalias>CORA</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Corynorhinus rafinesquii  was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>coto</attrlabl>
				<attalias>COTO</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Corynorhinus townsendii  was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>db_created_date</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Created Date</attalias>
				<attrdef>The date this record was created</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>db_creator</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Data Basin Creator</attalias>
				<attrdef>Data Basin User who created this record</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>dbasin_geom</attrlabl>
				<attalias>dbasin_geom</attalias>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>db_id</attrlabl>
				<attalias>db_id</attalias>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>det_id</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Detector ID</attalias>
				<attrdef>The name, number, or other identifier of the detector used to collect data (req'd)</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>det_mfg</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Detector Manufacturer</attalias>
				<attrdef>The manufacturer of the detector</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>det_model</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Detector Model</attalias>
				<attrdef>Model of detector used  to collect data</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>epfu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>EPFU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Eptesicus fuscus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>epfulano</attrlabl>
				<attalias>epfulano</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) identified as either EPFU or LANO on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>euma</attrlabl>
				<attalias>EUMA</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Euderma maculatum was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>eumaeupe</attrlabl>
				<attalias>eumaeupe</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either EUMA or EUPE on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>eumaidph</attrlabl>
				<attalias>eumaidph</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either EUMA or IDPH on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>eupe</attrlabl>
				<attalias>EUPE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Eumops perotis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>eupeidph</attrlabl>
				<attalias>eupeidph</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either EUPE or IDPH on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>eupenyma</attrlabl>
				<attalias>eupenyma</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either EUPE or NYMA on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>first_name</attrlabl>
				<attalias>First Name</attalias>
				<attrdef>First name of person who collected the data</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>idph</attrlabl>
				<attalias>IDPH</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Idionycteris phyllotis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>labl</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LABL</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Lasiurus blossevillii was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>lablpahe</attrlabl>
				<attalias>lablpahe</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either LABL or PAHE on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>labo</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LABO</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Lasiurus borealis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>labonyhu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>labonyhu</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either LABO or NYHU on a given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>labopesu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>labopesu</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either LABO or PESU on a given night </attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>laci</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LACI</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Lasiurus cinereus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>lacitabr</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LACI or TABR</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if at least one file, that could not be assigned to either LACI or TABR was assigned as belonging to the species couplet.  Enter 0 if no files were assigned to this couplet.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>lano</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LANO</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Lasionycteris noctivagans was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>lanotabr</attrlabl>
				<attalias>lanotabr</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either LANO or TABR on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>lase</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LASE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Lasiurus seminolus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>last_name</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Last  Name</attalias>
				<attrdef>Last Name of person who collected the data</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>laxa</attrlabl>
				<attalias>LAXA</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Lasiurus xanthinus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mic_ht</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Microphone Height</attalias>
				<attrdef>Height, above ground surface, microphone was placed during data collection</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mic_ht_units</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Microphone Height Units</attalias>
				<attrdef>Units used to report microphone height</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mic_type</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Microphone Type</attalias>
				<attrdef>Type of microphone used to collect data</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myarmyev</attrlabl>
				<attalias>myarmyev</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either MYAR or MYEV on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myau</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYAU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis austroriparius was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myca</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYCA</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis californicus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mycamyvo</attrlabl>
				<attalias>mycamyvo</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) identified as either MYCA or MYVO on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mycamyyu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYCA or MYYU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if at least one file, that could not be assigned to either MYCA or MYYU was assigned as belonging to the species couplet.  Enter 0 if no files were assigned to this couplet.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myci</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYCI</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis ciliolabrum was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myev</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYEV</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis evotis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myevmyth</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYEV or MYTH</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if at least one file, that could not be assigned to either MYEV or MYTH was assigned as belonging to the species couplet.  Enter 0 if no files were assigned to this couplet.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mygr</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYGR</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis grisescens was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myle</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYLE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis leibii was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mylu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYLU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis lucifugus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>mylumyvo</attrlabl>
				<attalias>mylumyvo</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) identified as either MYLU or MYVO on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myse</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYSE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis septentrionalis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myso</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYSO</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis sodalis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myth</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYTH</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis thysanodes was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myve</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYVE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis velifer was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myvo</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYVO</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis volans was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>myyu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>MYYU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Myotis yumanensis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>night</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Night</attalias>
				<attrdef>The date for the night on which data was collected (date night started)</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>nyfe</attrlabl>
				<attalias>NYFE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Nyctinomops femorosaccus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>nyfetabr</attrlabl>
				<attalias>nyfetabr</attalias>
				<attrdef>File(s) identified as either NYFE or TABR on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>nyhu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>NYHU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Nycticeius humeralis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>nyma</attrlabl>
				<attalias>NYMA</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Nyctinomops macrotis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pahe</attrlabl>
				<attalias>PAHE</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Parastrellus hesperus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pesu</attrlabl>
				<attalias>PESU</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Perimyotis subflavus was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>call_id_1</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Primary Call ID</attalias>
				<attrdef>Primary method used to identify echolocation calls to species</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>q10k</attrlabl>
				<attalias>q10k</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) assigned to a 10 kHz frequency group based on Fc</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>q15k</attrlabl>
				<attalias>q15k</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) assigned to a 15 kHz frequency group based on Fc</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>q25k</attrlabl>
				<attalias>q25k</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) assigned to a 25 kHz frequency group based on Fc</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>refl_type</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Reflector Type</attalias>
				<attrdef>Type of reflector used  (e.g. for weather-proofing)</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>reye</attrlabl>
				<attalias>reye</attalias>
				<attrdef>Recording(s) identified as either LABL or LAXA on given night</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>call_id_2</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Secondary Call ID</attalias>
				<attrdef>What additional methods were used to confirm call identifications?</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>site_id</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Site ID</attalias>
				<attrdef>The name (or other identifier) of the site where data was collected.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>tabr</attrlabl>
				<attalias>TABR</attalias>
				<attrdef>Enter 1 if Tadarida brasiliensis was recorded and identified on a given night and 0 on nights when it was not recorded.</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>x_coord</attrlabl>
				<attalias>X Coordinate</attalias>
				<attrdef>Longitude (decimal degrees) or UTM Easting where data was collected</attrdef>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>y_coord</attrlabl>
				<attalias>Y Coordinate</attalias>
				<attrdef>Latitude (decimal degrees) or UTM Northing where data was collected</attrdef>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<idinfo>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntemail>tweller@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Ted Weller</cntper>
					<cntorg>USDA Forest Service</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntpos>Ecologist</cntpos>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntemail>clong@batcon.org</cntemail>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Christen Long</cntper>
					<cntorg>Bat Conservation International</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntpos>BatAMP Project Manager</cntpos>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<descript>
			<abstract>Dataset represents presence of bat species as determined from acousticmonitoring.  Detectors were deployed at sites within National Forests according to A Plan for the North American Bat Monitoring Program (NABat) guidelines.Acoustic data were screened and analyzed by Christen Long, Bat Conservation International.  Data were analyzed to determine species present per night.  Map symbols represent detector locations.  For more information at each site, click the info tab, and then draw a box around your area of interest.</abstract>
		</descript>
		<useconst>This work is licensed under a  Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License .</useconst>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekey>acoustic detection,us forest service,lasiurus blossevillii,myotis evotis,pallid bat,usda forest service,nabat,myotis volans,myotis thysanodes,mexican free-tailed bat,myotis lucifugus,bat amp,myotis californicus,lasionycteris noctivagans,california,hoary bat,myotis yumanensis,myotis ciliolabrum,lasiurus cinereus,silver-haired bat,corynorhinus townsendii,batamp,spotted bat</themekey>
			</theme>
		</keywords>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<onlink>https://databasin.org/datasets/66b456d239904db99ac5860bc5882a8a</onlink>
				<title>US Forest Service NABat Stationary Detectors 2019</title>
				<origin>Ted Weller</origin>
				<origin>Christen Long</origin>
				<origin>Suzanne DeRosier</origin>
				<origin>Janae Thomas</origin>
				<origin>Todd Russel</origin>
				<origin>Janie Agyagos</origin>
				<origin>Francisco Anaya</origin>
				<origin>Christina Akins</origin>
				<origin>Stephanie Rainey</origin>
				<origin>Cassandra Marszal</origin>
				<origin>Mony Sea</origin>
				<origin>Theresa Lowe</origin>
				<origin>Linda Angerer</origin>
				<origin>Todd Johnson</origin>
				<origin>Susan Yasuda</origin>
				<origin>Megan Solus</origin>
				<origin>Jason Kelton</origin>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<southbc>3971943.08779</southbc>
				<northbc>8304399.25092</northbc>
				<eastbc>-7938514.97728</eastbc>
				<westbc>-15548315.3336</westbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
	</idinfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distliab>No warranty is made by Data Basin for use of this dataset.  No warranty is made by Data Basin regarding the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of this dataset. In no event shall Data Basin have any liability whatsoever for payment of any consequential, incidental, indirect, special, or tort damages of any kind, including, but not limited to, any loss of profits arising out of the use or reliance on the geographic or attribute data contained within this dataset or arising out of the delivery, installation, operation, or support by Data Basin.</distliab>
		<techpreq>Desktop GIS software.</techpreq>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>https://databasin.org/datasets/66b456d239904db99ac5860bc5882a8a</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
						<accinstr>Download from https://databasin.org</accinstr>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>Feature Layer</formname>
					<filedec>No compression applied</filedec>
					<formspec>Feature Layer</formspec>
				</digtinfo>
			</digform>
			<ordering>Download from https://databasin.org</ordering>
			<fees>None</fees>
		</stdorder>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntemail>databasin_admin@consbio.org</cntemail>
				<cntperp>
					<cntorg>Data Basin</cntorg>
					<cntper>Data Basin Administrator</cntper>
				</cntperp>
				<cntvoice>541-757-0687</cntvoice>
				<cntaddr>
					<country>USA</country>
					<city>Corvallis</city>
					<postal>97333</postal>
					<address>136 SW Washington Ave, Suite 202</address>
					<addrtype>physical address</addrtype>
					<state>OR</state>
				</cntaddr>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
	</distinfo>
</metadata>
